Emmanuel Ememe

Coventry, United Kingdom +447742101130 | ememeemmanuel3@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-ememe-b649a8176/

Professional Profile

A Dedicated and Efficient full stack Developer with Two years' experience in application Layers, Presentation layers and databases. Proficient in M.E.A.N and M.E.R.N stack and a certified AWS cloud Practitioner, AWS Solutions Architect and AWS Developer Associate. Having a background in Mechanical Engineering (Product Design) and have led a Team of 4-12 people across the Technology, Business and Design Departments. An Aspiring Olympic Gold Medallist in the 100 and 200 meters sprint.

Key Competencies

Scrum, Web Markup (H.T.M.L.5, C.S.S.3), JavaScript, JQUERY, BOOTSTRAP, JS Frameworks(React, Angular JS, Vue), Linux, Node.js, Typescript, GraphQL, Jest Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Testing, Git and GitHub, Python, AWS console, Basic UI/UX Design, Database Technology(Mongo DB, , MySQL), Solid works, Ansys, Catia, NX CAD, Siemens Planning, Problem Solving, Time Management, Communication and Attention to Details, Crisis Management, Leadership, Logical Thinking, Organisation, Teamwork, Multi-tasking, Patience, Stress Management, Research, Supervising, Non-verbal communication, Verbal-communication, Safety Conscious, Keeping Records, Financial Accounting.

Qualifications

- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- AWS Certified` Solutions Architect
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Scrum Master
- Certified Full-Stack web Developer Knowledge-Hut
- Product Design Engineer Skill Lync
- MScs. Business Administration with Human Resource Management Ulster University
- MScs. Engineering Management Coventry University
- BScs. Mechanical Engineering Eastern Mediterranean University

Career History

Mar 2020 – Date - Full-Stack Developer Toptal

Toptal is a global online talent marketplace that links businesses with the top independent software developers, designers, and consultants.

A Self-employed Professional building websites and mobile applications to meet the needs and specifications of clients.

- Developed 100+ full-stack web applications to analyse and process Data for different clients.
- Designed and created a knowledge management platform on a knowledge graph, Utilizing a range of technologies, including Node.js, Typescript and React.
- Conducted unit and load testing for High profile customer facing applications which reduced system failure rate by 70%

Mar 2019 — Nov 2019 - Project Manager Nigerian National Petroleum Cooperation, Port Harcourt

The Nigerian National Petroleum Co-operation harnesses Nigeria's oil and gas reserves for Sustainable National Development. Their Activities includes Drilling and processing of Crude oil/petroleum to be Used to produce power in the country or Exported to other Countries.

My role was to plan, co-ordinate and manage oil and gas projects, working out Scopes and cost for projects, providing leadership across projects and ensure clear agreements of objectives.

- Defined Project Proposals and determined time, quality, safety and cost scope with 95% accuracy.
- Directed 6 drilling Projects from start to completion, managing Project budget of up to N900 million (Naira).
- Utilised MS project to plan, manage and track multiple projects simultaneously.

Jan 2018 — Dec 2018 - Mechanical Engineer Abuja Municipal Area Council, Abuja, Nigeria

The Abuja municipal Area council is an Organisation responsible for enlightening members of the public on the necessity of community education in the area council, investigating cases of illegal withdrawal of pupils from schools, They are responsible for Handling development projects in the council.

My role as a mechanical engineer was to design power-producing Machines such as electric generators, steam and combustion engines and gas turbines that will give power to communities that lack power supply.

- Led project Team in analysing projects with customers, Increasing customer satisfaction score by 6%
- Managed and Participated in Quality Assurance and Quality Control process for the team, helping decrease team mistakes by 12%
- Increased overall team efficiency by 9% by providing extensive project training.

Apr 2017 — Nov 2017 - Secretary Edo State Sports Council, Benin City, Nigeria.

The primary duties of the Sports Council is to encourage interest in and participation in sport and to plan competitions and events in their local communities. They also select representatives from various events to represent the country and allocates awards.

I was responsible for taking records of athletes performances and Organising the order of events for a competition day. I also engaged in fund raising for Charity and handicapped Athletes.

- Planned the 2017 Nigerian National Sports Festival Event Timetable
- Raised N12million for Para-athletes. This motivated them to train harder and improve their improved performance.
- Kept Accurate records of all performing athletes and selected the best Athletes to represent the country at the world Championships.

Languages

English (Fluent)

French (Conversational)

Turkish (Fluent)